[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以我需要说一些关于性能的事情，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So I need to say something about performance,
因为我有时听到需要表演作为借口
because I sometimes hear the need for performance as the excuse for
为什么我们不能有好的风格。
why we can't have good style.
事实证明，这些论点都是错误的。
It turns out those arguments are all wrong.
特定于性能的代码通常是CRUFFY
Performance specific code is usually crufty
因为我们正在从代码中去除通用性。
because we're removing generality from the code.
我们增加了通过代码的路径，
We're increasing paths through the code,
这使得测试和维护都变得更加困难。
which makes testing and maintenance all much harder to do.
干净的代码更容易推理。
Clean code is much easier to reason about.
因此，我们应该尽可能地保持代码的干净，尽可能长的时间。
So we should try to keep our code as clean as we can, for as long as we can.
斯坦福大学的Donald Knuth说过早的优化是一切的根源
Donald Knuth of Stanford said that premature optimization is the root of all
邪恶，这是真的。
evil, which is true.
我们不应该试图优化任何代码，直到我们已经测量了它。
We should not attempt to optimize any code until we have measured it.
然后我们应该做优化，然后我们应该再次测量。
We should then do the optimization, we should then measure again.
如果我们没有得到显著的改善，
And if we did not get a significant improvement,
然后，我们应该将更改视为bug，并将其退回。
then we should consider the change to be a bug and back it out.
如果我们将CRUFT添加到代码库的原因是为了让它更快，
If the reason we added cruft to the code base was to make it faster,
如果我们实际上没有获得显著的性能提升，
if we didn't actually obtain the significant performance increase,
那么它就失败了，我们应该删除那个代码。
then it fails, and we should remove that code.
所以量两次，切一次。
So measure twice, cut once.
事实证明，大多数代码对性能的影响可以忽略不计，所以
It turns out most code has a negligible impact on performance, so
我们应该只为优化花费最多时间的代码而烦恼。
we should only bother with optimizing the code that is taking the most time.
您只有限的时间进行优化，所以
You have only a limited amount of time for doing optimization, so
你不想浪费时间优化那些无关紧要的代码。
you don't wanna waste that time optimizing code that doesn't matter.
你需要优化你的优化。
You need to optimize your optimizing.
最后，算法替换比代码篡改更有效。
And finally, algorithm replacement is vastly more effective than code fiddling.
所以如果你的代码很慢，因为你有一个n平方的循环，
So if your code is slow because you've got an n squared loop, fiddling with
内环的细节对显着增加n没有影响。
the details of the inner loop will have no effect on significantly increasing n.
唯一可行的方法是将代码替换为不同的
The only thing that could work is replacing that code with a different
算法，可能是一个nlogn算法，然后可以得到一个更大的n。
algorithm in maybe an n log n algorithm, which can then get you a much larger n.
并且，如果代码具有以下条件，那么这种更改就容易得多
And that kind of change is much easier to do if the code has
尚未预先优化。
not already been pre-optimized.
编程是人类所做的最复杂的事情。
Programming is the most complicated thing that humans do.
计算机程序必须是完美的，而人类并不擅长完美，
Computer programs must be perfect and humans are not good at perfect,
尤其是我。
especially me.
我是一个有很大缺陷的人，但是我是一个很好的程序员，但是
I am a deeply flawed human being, but I'm a pretty good programmer, but
它需要大量的努力和纪律。
it requires a tremendous amount of effort and discipline.
因此，设计一种编程风格需要纪律。
So designing a programming style demands discipline.
它并不是因为喜欢或漂亮或熟悉而选择特征。
It is not selecting features because they are liked or pretty or familiar.
这是因为它可以帮助你降低错误率。
It's because it helps you to reduce your error rate.
另一种选择是在深渊中花费更多的时间。
The alternative is spending more time in the abyss.
你知道我在说什么。
You know what I'm talking about.
那就是我们下到的寒冷，黑暗，伤害的地方，我们去的地方
That's that cold, dark, hurtful place we descend into where we go and
与恶魔战斗并杀死虫子。
battle the demons and kill the bugs.
当我第一次开始编程的时候，感觉很棒。
When I first started programming, it was wonderful.
我突然顿悟了。
I was having this epiphany.
我以为我有了一种新的方式来理解世界上的一切，而且
I thought I had this new way of understanding everything in the world, and
我觉得很棒。
I thought it was great.
我认为每个人都应该学习如何做到这一点，因为这真的是令人兴奋的事情。
I thought everybody should learn how to do this, cuz this is really exciting stuff.
我再也不相信了。
I don't believe that anymore.
我认为我们能够进行编程，因为有一些严肃的事情
I think that we are able to do programming because there's something seriously
我们有问题。&gt；&gt；[笑]
wrong with us. &gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：普通人
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Normal people
我不能这么做。
can't do this.
如果一个正常人掉进了深渊，他们会马上回来说，
If a normal person goes down into the abyss, they come right back up and say,
我在换专业。
I'm changing majors.
我不知道你们这些人怎么了。
I don't know what's wrong with you people.
我要离开这里。
I'm out of here.
我们之所以能做到这一点，是因为我们患有健忘症，我们
We're able to do this because of this amnesia thing that we suffer from, that we
忘记我们在那里度过了多少时间，忘记了我们在那里有多糟糕。
forget how much time we spend down there and how awful it is when we're down there.
这就是让我们再次下去的原因。
And that's what allows us to go down there again.
而且，我们是极大的乐观主义者，我们认为我们可以
Also, we're tremendous optimists, that we think that we can actually
去那里，赢得比赛，然后回来，这是一件很棒的事情。
go down there and win and come back, and that's a great thing.
我认为你不能既是乐观主义者又是程序员。
I don't think you can be an optimist and be a programmer.
或者你必须是一个乐观主义者才能成为一个程序员，这是必要的。
Or you gotta be an optimist to be a programmer, it's just necessary.
这也是为什么我们不能安排有价值的废话，对吧？
That's also why we can't schedule worth crap, right?
那要花多长时间？
How long is that gonna take?
而且进行得很好，它大约有那么多击键，所以
And go well, it's about that many keystrokes, so
[声音]应该要花那么长时间。
[SOUND] it is should take about that long.
我们忘了这件事，对吧？
We forget about that, right?
那是大部分时间去的地方。
That's where most of the time goes.
所以如果你想更有效率
So if you want to be more effective,
更有效率，找到一种远离那里的方法，这就是最大的胜利。
more productive, figuring out a way to stay out of there, that's the big win.
弄清楚如何减少击键次数是无关紧要的，对吧？
Figuring out how to reduce your keystrokes is irrelevant, right?
你想优化那些占用你时间的东西。
You wanna optimize the thing that's taking your time.
占用你时间的不是打字，而是打字。
And the thing that's taking your time isn't the typing, it's that.
因此，JSLint风格是由自动检测缺陷的需求驱动的。
So the JSLint style was driven by the need to automatically detect defects.
可以隐藏缺陷的表单被认为是有缺陷的。
And that forms that can hide defects are considered defective.
即使他们当时不是虫子。
Even if they're not bugs that instant.
所以当我开发JSLint时，
So when I was developing JSLint,
Usenet上有一个叫做comped out lang.javascript的东西。
there was a thing called comped out lang.javascript on the Usenet.
有无数的人说，我的程序不起作用。
And there was an endless stream of people saying, my program doesn't work.
有人能告诉我为什么吗？
Can someone tell me why?
所以我会把它们扔进JSLint，然后
And so I would take them and I'd throw them in JSLint, and
有时候它会去，就在那里。
sometimes it'd go, there it is.
有时它会去，它不能，为什么呢？
And sometimes it'd go, it couldn't, why is that?
有时是因为他们使用的形式
And sometimes it was because they were using forms which made
进一步分析该方案是不可能的。
further analysis of the program impossible.
最终，我很不情愿地决定，
And eventually, reluctantly, I came to decide that,
如果你是这样写的，你不需要这样写，那就有问题了，
if you're writing that way and you don't need to, then that's a problem,
因为我们想让我们的程序让错误脱颖而出。
because we want to make our programs make the errors stand out.
你可以通过一直写得更好来做到这一点。
And you can do that by writing better all the time.
所以分设语言的想法并不是一个原创的想法，
So the idea of sub-setting a language is not an original idea,
对于几乎每一种语言，您都希望将其划分为子集。
that for virtually every language you wanna subset it.
据说只有疯子才会使用所有的C+。
It's been said only a madman would use all of C++.
也有人说只有疯子才会使用C+，但这是一种
It's also been said only a madman would use C++, but that's a for
下次吧。
another time.
让每个人都使用相同的子集是有好处的。
And there is something nice about having everybody using the same subset.
每个编写C+的团队都会计算出他们想要使用多少语言。
Every team writing C++ will figure out how much of the language they want to use.
这是很好的，直到他们现在不得不接管别人的代码和
And that's fine until they now have to take over someone else's code and
去吧，朋友，垃圾，你不需要处理那些东西。
go, friends, crap, you don't have to deal with that stuff.
所以如果我们可以让每个人使用相同的子集，
So if we could get everybody using the same subset,
这使得互操作性更加容易。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：So
that makes interoperability a lot easier. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So
会有虫子。
there will be bugs.
我不能保证如果你采用一种更好的编程风格，你就可以没有bug，
I'm not promising that you can be bug free if you adopt a better programming style,
但是你可以把赔率转移到你的有利位置，你肯定会赢，而且
but you can move the odds to your favor and you definitely win, and
你这样做是免费的。
you do that at no cost.